A Guide to the Charles Burchard Collection, 1935-1989, n.d.
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
- Series V: Personal Papers, 1935-1989, n.d.
  - Subseries C: Correspondence with Individuals, 1939-1989
    - Family Correspondence, 1952-1989 (Box 16, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence relating to Walter Gropius
      - Gropius Lecture, "Rebuilding Our Communities," Insititue of Design Publication, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 23)
      - Walter Gropius: "Blueprint for an Architect's Training", 1952 (Box 16, Folder 33)
      - Walter Gropius: Correspondence, 1955-1968 (Box 16, Folder 24)
      - Walter Gropius: Brochures & Memors, 1963-1982 (Box 16, Folder 25)
      - Burchard: Talks on Gropius, 1964-1989 (Box 16, Folder 26)
      - Walter Gropius: "Scope of Total Architecture", 1970 (Box 16, Folder 27)
      - Walter Gropius: "Buildings, Plans, Projects 1906-1969", 1972 (Box 16, Folder 28)
      - Ise Gropius, 1972-1983 (Box 16, Folder 30)
      - Gropius Funds (Box 16, Folder 31)
      - Writings on Walter Gropius (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Klaus Herdeg: The Decorated Diagram, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Lepley v. New Jersey State BoA, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 44)
    - William "Bill" Lyman, 1945-1986 (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - Chester Nagel, 1946-1986 (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - Chester Nagel, Professional Projects, 1950-1977 (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - I. M. Pei, 1952-1987 (Box 16, Folder 40)
    - Ladislav Rado, 1984-1986 (Box 16, Folder 45)
    - Reinhard, Hofmeister, & Walquist Architects, 1939-1953 (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - Robert Venturi, 1971-1979 (Box 16, Folder 43)
    - Letter: Mrs. Frank Lloyd Wright, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - Subseries D: Certificates, 1927-1981
    - Baptism and Confirmation certificates, 1927 (Folder 7)
    - Alpha Rho Chi fraternity, 1969 (Folder 8)
    - Society of the Friends of Wren, 1969 (Folder 8)
    - Harris County Sheriff's Department (Houston, TX), 1981 (Folder 8)
    - The Exchange Club of Cincinnati (Folder 7)
- Series VI: Multimedia & Audio/Visual, 1941-1985, n.d.
  Series VI: Multimedia & Audio/Visual, 1941-1985, n.d., consists of three subseries. Subseries A: Slides, 1951-1985, n.d., contains personal images from 1973 and 1974; slides used by Burchard in his teaching; images of student and professional projects; extensive slides from professional travel in Europe and Mexico. This subseries also contains three boxes of glass plate negatives and lantern slides which include travel images, professional research, and student projects. This subseries is arranged into sub-subseries based on original use and format.
  Subseries B: Oversize Materials, 1941, c.1950s, includes a painting owned by Burchard and a set of boards with photographs from various architecture projects. This series is arranged by material type.
  Subseries C: Videotapes & Audio Cassettes, 1977, 1980, n.d., consists of a 1/2" reel video of a lecture by Burchard, three UCA videocassettes with lectures from the 1980 Burchard Symposium, and several microcassette recordings. This subseries is arranged by material type.
  - Subseries A: Slides, 1951-1985, n.d.
    - Sub-subseries 1: Family, Friends, and Blacksburg, 1973-1974 (Box 18)
    - Sub-subseries 2: Professional & Educational Materials
      - Built Projects (Box 21)
      - Education and Curriculum (Box 19)
      - Slides and Lectures (Box 22)
    - Sub-subseries 3: Travel
      - Europe Travel: Italy, Britain, Belgium, France, Greece, Switzerland, 1951 (Box 17)
      - Europe Travel: Greece, Italy, France, Switzerland, Macedonia, Croatia, 1965-1975 (Box 20)
      - Europe Travel, 1965-1975 (Box 19)
      - Mexico and Austria (Box 23)
      - Scenic Travel (Box 18)
    - Sub-subseries 4: Glass plate negatives and lantern slides, c.1930s-1960s, n.d. (Box 35, Box 36, Box 37)
      Note
      Please note: Only a portion of the glass plate negatives and lantern slides are labeled and they have not be inventoried to the item level. In general, they include locations, site, and plans relating to building projects; travel locations; and student project materials. Dated materials cover the 1930s-1960s, but it is possible plates and slides cover additional time periods.
  - Subseries B: Oversize Materials, 1941, c.1950s
    - Chalchuhtililne painting, 1941 (Folder 3)
    - Four boards with mounted photographs from architecture projects, c.1950s (Folder 3)
  - Subseries C: Videotapes & Audio Cassettes, 1977, 1980, n.d. (Box 24)
    - Accreditation & Dean Burchard "On the Future of Architecture" [1/2" open reel video tape], 1977
    - Burchard Symposium, William Porter (MIT) [UCA60 Videocassette], April 1980
    - Burchard Symposium, Constance Perin 1 & 2 [UCA60 Videocassette], April 1980
    - Burchard Symposium, San Jose: Introduction, Robert Harris [UCA60 Videocassette], April 1980
    - Microcassettes labeled: "test tape," "Rordam," and "Nancy Seagle" (Box 34)
- Series VII: Artifacts, 1971-1985, n.d. (Box 34)
  Series VII: Artifacts, 1971-1985, n.d., contains a collection of small objects, including medals awarded to Burchard by professional organizations, items from his professional career, and some small artifacts relating to the history of the College of Architecture. This series is arranged in alphabetical order by item title/description.
  - Alpha Rho Chi coin, 1979
  - American Institute of Architects Fellow medal
  - American Institute of Architects, William C. Noland Award, 1984
  - Collection of Burchard's architecture stamps
  - Flipbook, 1979
  - Kyushu University Medal
  - The New Horizon award, 1981
  - T-Square with MIT case
  - Virginia Cultural Laureate Education medal, 1986
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University Distinguished Achievement Award, 1985
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University Fifteen Year Service Award (framed) and pin, 1979
  - VPI&SU College of Archtecture cube, 1971
  - Wall-hanging